(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
残響散歌
作詞：aimerrhythm 作曲：飛内将大
Zankyou Sanka
Lyrics: aimerrhythm Composition: Masahiro Tobinai
誰が袖に咲く紅花
Whose sleeve does the crimson flower bloom on?
ただそこに藍を落とした
I simply dropped indigo there
派手に色を溶かす夜に 銀朱の月を添えて
Adding a vermilion moon to the night where colors dissolve gaudily
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling
躓くごとに強くなった
I grew stronger with every stumble
光も痛みも怒りも
The light, the pain, and the anger too
全部抱きしめて
Embracing it all
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you're not chosen, then just choose yourself
声よ 轟け 夜のその向こうへ
O voice, roar out beyond the night
涙で滲んでた あんなに遠くの景色まで 響き渡れ
Resonate to that distant scenery that was blurred by tears
何を奏でて
What to play?
誰に届けたくて 不確かなままでいい
To whom to deliver? It's fine to remain uncertain
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions
どんなに長い葛藤も
No matter how long the conflict
歌と散れ 残響
Scatter with the song, reverberation
ただ一人舞う千夜
Dancing alone for a thousand nights
違えない帯を結べば
If you tie a sash that won't go wrong
派手な色も負かすように 深紅の香こそあわれ
As if to defeat even gaudy colors, the deep red scent is so moving
この先どんな辛い時も
In any hard times ahead
口先よりも胸を張って
Hold your head high instead of just talking
抱いた夢の灯を全部 辿るだけ
Simply follow all the lights of the dreams you held
逃げ出すため ここまで来たんじゃないだろう
It wasn't to run away that we came all this way, was it?
（ボーカル：森カリオペ）
(Vocal: Mori Calliope)
声を枯らして 燃える花のように
Letting out my voice, like a burning flower
闇間を照らしたら 曖昧すぎる世界も
Lighting up the darkness, even this world that's too vague
不鮮明にして
Will become indistinct
夜を数えて 朝を描くような
Counting the nights, like sketching the morning
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
I'll make a vivid sound
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret
どんなに高い限界も
No matter how high the limit
かき消して
I'll drown them out
残響だだだだだだだだだだだ
Resonance da-da-da...
はい！ということで、ホロ・アコースティックライブ・イン・サマー、始まりましたー！
Alright! And with that, holoAcousticLive in Summer has officially begun!
イェーイ！
Yay!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
始まったー！始まったよー！
It's started! It's finally started!
はい。ということで、お越しくださっている皆様、ありがとうございます！
Yes. So, to everyone who has come to watch, thank you so much!
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you!
それでは最初に、今日はね、色んな一緒に歌っていただくメンバーがいっぱいいるんですけれども、自己紹介をそれぞれさせていただきたいと思います。
First of all, we have many members singing with us today, so we'd like to introduce ourselves.
お願いしますー！
Please do!
はい。まずはホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりだよー！よろしくお願いします！
Okay. First off, from Hololive's 6th Gen, the brains of Secret Society holoX, it's Hakui Koyori! Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！助手君ー！
Yay! Joshu-kun!
はい！そして1曲目から来ていただいたのは、まずミオ先輩！
Right! And joining us from the very first song, Mio-senpai!
うちうち！うちだよ！大神ミオだよー！ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオです。どうもー！
Uchi uchi! It's me! I'm Ookami Mio! From Hololive Gamers, I'm Ookami Mio. Hello everyone!
イェーイ！よろしくお願いします、ミオだよー！
Yay! Nice to be here, it's Mio!
そしてー！私！わあ、ちょっと待って、ちゃんと自己紹介しないと。
And next! Me! Oh, wait, I need to introduce myself properly.
皆さん！森カリオペです。ホロライブEnglishの死神ですです。よろしくお願いいたします！楽しもう！
Everyone! It's Mori Calliope. I'm the Grim Reaper of Hololive English-desu desu. Nice to meet you! Let's have fun!
イェーイ！エブリワン！
Yay! Everyone!
はい。お忙しい中、こうしてライブ出演していただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for taking time out of your busy schedules to perform in this live.
いや、こちらこそ呼んでくれてありがとう！ありがとうございます！
No, thank you for inviting us! We're glad to be here!
はい。そしてですね、今回はなんと、ピアノも生演奏でお届けさせていただきます。こよりの生誕ライブでも演奏していただきました。
Also, for this performance, we'll be featuring live piano accompaniment. They also played for my birthday live.
ウイングさんでーす！
It's Wing-san!
わあ、素敵です！美しい！
Wow, how wonderful! Beautiful!
ハンサム！素敵！美しい！
Handsome! Wonderful! Beautiful!
はい。このライブはですね、最初から最後まで完全生放送、そして生演奏でお届けさせていただきますので、よしなによろしくお願いいたします。
Yes. This live show will be fully broadcast live from start to finish with live music, so we hope you enjoy it.
ま、なんでこのライブをやることになったかと言いますとですね。普通のライブ、生誕ライブとか周年ライブって、ダンスレッスン頑張ったりとか、
Now, let me tell you why we decided to do this live. For usual lives, like birthday or anniversary shows, we work hard on dance lessons,
ゲストパートは収録でやったりとか、後ろのモニター作ったりとか、とにかく準備が大変なんですよね。
guest parts are often pre-recorded, and we have to create content for the monitors... the preparation is just immense.
めっちゃ大変！いっぱいやること！
It's so much work! So many things to do!
そう、あって。ま、一つ作るのにすごく時間がかかるんですけど、アコースティックライブだったら集まって、演奏していただいて、歌ったら当日でいけるんじゃね？というのを、ちょっとチャレンジしてみたという形になっております。
Right. It takes a lot of time to put one together. But for an acoustic live, I thought, 'Can't we just gather, have someone play, and sing on the day of?' So we're taking on that challenge today.
素敵なチャレンジ！
What a wonderful challenge!
はい。でも歌っていただくので、皆さんには大変なんですけれども。いや、楽しかったよね！本当に楽しかった！
Yes. Though it's hard on everyone because you have to sing live. But it's been fun, hasn't it? Really fun!
嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
I'm so glad! Thank you!
ミオちゃんと、お揃いみたいな感じだね。そうそうそう。でもなんか真ん中にこよりが入ることで、なんか良い感じにまとまってるね。
Mio-chan and I look like we're matching. Right, right. But with Koyori in the middle, it balances out quite nicely.
そう、このカラーリング的にね、この並びになりました。素敵ですね！
Yeah, because of the color scheme, we ended up in this order. It's lovely!
もしかしたら今ね、ちょっとあの、コメントが止まっちゃってるかもしれないんですけど。コメントが壊れちゃった。壊れちゃってるかもしれないんですけど、
By the way, it seems like the comments might have stopped for a bit. The comments broke. They might be broken, but...
また動き出すと思うので、皆様ちょっと様子見つつ。あと、トレンド今3位！早い！序盤なのにもうトレンド3位！
I think they'll start moving again, so please keep an eye out. Also, we're currently #3 on trending! So fast! We've only just started and we're already #3!
速い！はい。そんな感じでハッシュタグはこちら「#holoAcousticLive」。使ってください！お願いします！
That was quick! Yes. So please use the hashtag "#holoAcousticLive". Please do!
スクショも感想も全部見ますので、是非ツイートしてください。よろしくお願いします！お願いします！
I'll be looking at all your screenshots and impressions, so please tweet them. We're counting on you!
さて1曲目は残響散歌でしたけれども、ミオ先輩どうでしたか？
Now, our first song was 'Zankyo Sanka'. How was it for you, Mio-senpai?
はい。えーと、すごい、あの、こうやって、なんだろうね、一緒に歌うのめっちゃ楽しいよね。楽しい！
Yes. Well, it's really... how should I say, it's so much fun to sing together like this. It is fun!
歌に集中できますからね、このアコースティックだと。なんかこうカッコいい感じの曲をこうやって歌うの、すごい楽しかったなって。
Since it's acoustic, we can really focus on the singing. It was a lot of fun to perform such a cool song this way.
...澪も大好きだし...
...I love it too...
こよも最近ね、歌めっちゃ頑張ってて、凄く上手くなったからさ。
Koyori's been working so hard on her singing lately, and she's gotten so good.
嬉しい〜！超緊張しちゃった一曲目だけど。
I'm so happy! I was so nervous for the first song though.
ちょっと一緒に歌ってて凄いテンション上がりました。ありがとうございました。
I got so pumped up singing together. Thank you so much.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
カリ先輩どうですか？
Calli-senpai, how was it for you?
かっこいい曲大好きです！イェーイ！
I love cool songs! Yeah!
実は、あの、この曲あんまり知らなかったから、練習した...
Actually, I didn't know this song very well, so I practiced...
練習した？知ってたけど...
You practiced? You knew it but...
歌ったことなかったから、
Since I'd never sung it before,
何回も練習して、マジで！？
I practiced over and over. Seriously!?
少しずつ上手くなってきたかもしれないけど、頑張りました！
I might have gotten a bit better at it, but I did my best!
素晴らしい！
Amazing!
めっちゃもう元々知ってると勝手に思うぐらい上手だったよね。
You were so good I just assumed you knew it all along.
完璧でした！ありがとうございました！
It was perfect! Thank you!
かっこいい曲です。こちらこそ。
It's a cool song. Likewise.
Nice choice.
コメント生き返ってる！
The comments are coming back to life!
生き返った、よかったよかった。見てる見てる。
They're back, that's good. We see you.
ということでね、こより的には、今日は夏っぽい曲を揃えて、
So, for my part, I wanted to pick some summery songs for today,
インサマーな感じでやりたいなと思って選曲してたんですけど、
and I put together a setlist with an "in summer" feel.
結構ね夏の曲ってエモい曲が多くて、
Summer songs often have an "emotional" feel to them.
しっとりね。
Mellow ones.
でも一発目はやっぱりかっこよくバーンって盛り上げて始めたいなと思ったので、
But for the first one, I wanted to start with a bang and get everyone excited!
最高。
That was the best.
これを選びまして、ちょっとかっこいい二人に挟まれてこより大丈夫かな〜みたいな感じだったんですけど、
So I chose this one. I was a bit worried about being between two cool people,
一緒に歌えてめちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
but singing together was so much fun!
ありがとうございました！ということで、それではそろそろ次の曲に行くメンバーを、
Thank you! All right, let's call out the next member.
お呼びしたいと思いますよ！
It's time to bring her out!
ビジュー！
Bijou!
ワ！ワ！ワ！
Wah! Wah! Wah!
かわいいね〜！あら〜！
So cute! Oh my!
はい、ではイントロデュース、オッケー？
Okay, go ahead and introduce yourself.
えっ、ボンビジュー！ホロライブEnglish -Advent-の輝く宝石、古石ビジューだよ！
Uh, Bonjour! I'm Koseki Bijou, the Shining Jewel from hololive English -Advent-!
キラキラ、古石！
Kira-kira, Koseki!
キラキラ〜！
Kira-kira!
Thank you for coming today!
ちっちゃい！すごいちっちゃい！
She's so small! So tiny!
ありがとう！キュート。
Thank you! Cute.
ね、この後ビジュー、シンギング、どう？
So, Biboo is singing next, right? How are you feeling?
ちょっと緊張。
A little nervous.
かわいい〜！
So cute!
はい、ではこの後はですね、2曲続けてお届けさせていただくんですけども、
Next, we have two songs in a row for you.
次の曲はカリ先輩とビジューの二人で！
The next song is by Calli-senpai and Bijou!
Oh my god! Represent! Represent!
エモくない感じなのかな？ヒップホップなのかな？
It's not exactly "emo"... maybe hip-hop?
ロック！
Rock!
さあ、どんな曲なのか。ロックンロール！ロックンロール！
Let's see what it is. Rock and roll! Rock and roll!
二人のね、声にめちゃくちゃ合う曲を選んでますので、
I picked a song that really suits their voices,
堪能していただきたい。
so please enjoy it.
セトリは決めさせていただきました。
I was the one who decided on the setlist.
ありがとう。堪能していただければ嬉しいなと思います。
Thank you. I hope you enjoy it.
では我々は一緒に、客席行きましょう。
All right, we're going to head over to the audience seats.
ゆっくり休んでください！頑張ってね二人とも！
Take it easy! Good luck, you two!
頑張ります！見てるよ！See you!
We'll do our best! We'll be watching! See you!
Just you and me now.
I guess it's just us now.
English time! English time! だいじょうぶすか？
English time! English time! You okay?
だいじょうぶです！英語話せるかな？まあ話さなくてもいいよ。
I'm fine! Can I speak English? Well, I don't really have to.
楽しもう。Let's sing a song.
Let's just have fun. Let's sing a song.
オッケー。Rock.
Okay. Rock.
Rock and roll. We're rock and rolling!
And now, please listen everyone to "風といっしょに".
And now, please listen everyone to "Kaze to Issho ni".
風といっしょに
作詞：戸田昭吾 作曲：たなかひろかず
Kaze to Issho ni
Lyrics: Shogo Toda Composition: Hirokazu Tanaka
歩きつづけて
Keep on walking
どこまで行くの
How far will you go?
風にたずねられて
Asked by the wind
立ち止まる
I stop in my tracks
ひとつ　つめたい太鼓
One cold drum
ドクンと鳴って
Beats "thump"
たった　ひとつ
Just one
いつの
At what point
いのちはじまった
did life begin?
やがて　なにかをもとめて
Eventually, seeking something
ちいさなてのひらを　ひろげ
You spread your small palms
きみはすぐに見つけたね
And you found it right away, didn't you?
きみじゃない　だれかを
Someone who wasn't you
だいじょうぶだと　いわれ
Told that everything was alright
うそがふえたけど
The lies increased, but
たったひとつの
From your one and only
ふるさとたびだった
hometown, you set out
いまも　なにかをもとめて
Even now, seeking something
大きなひとみ　かがやいて
Your large eyes sparkling
きみのポケットのなかには
Inside your pocket
きみじゃない　だれかとの
There's something shared with someone
いくつもの出会い
Countless encounters
いくつもの別れ
Countless partings
まぼろしのような思い出も
Even the phantom-like memories
いとしい
are precious
あるきつづけて
Keep on walking
どこまでゆくの
how far will you go?
かぜにたずねられて
Asked by the wind
そらを見る
you look at the sky
あるきつづけて
Keep on walking
どこまでゆこうか
how far shall we go?
かぜといっしょにまた
Together with the wind again
あるきだそう
let's start walking
だいちふみしめ
Stepping firmly on the earth
どこまでもゆこう
let's go as far as we can
めざしたあのゆめを
Until that dream we aimed for
つかむまで
is within our grasp
だいちふみしめ
Stepping firmly on the earth
どこまでもゆこう
let's go as far as we can
めざしたあのゆめを
Until that dream we aimed for
つかむまで
is within our grasp
ラララ...
La la la...
花に亡霊
作詞・作曲：n-buna
Ghost in a Flower
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten
夏の木陰に座ったまま
As we sat in the shade of summer
アイスを口に放り込んで
Tossing ice cream into our mouths
風を待っていた
waiting for the breeze
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
How the whole world is full of lies
本当の価値をふたりで
And how we laughed about going
探しに行こうと笑ったこと
to find true value together
忘れないように
So that I don't forget
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that things left in physical form aren't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming
僕は描いてる　眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I'm drawing it—what reflected in my eyes was a summer ghost
花に亡霊
Ghost in a Flower
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
forgetting all my memories,
浅い呼吸をする
I take shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, becoming like summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten,
夏の木陰に座った頃
back when we sat in the shade of summer,
遠くの丘から顔を出した雲があったじゃないか
how there were clouds peeking from over the distant hills.
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to grab hold of them,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
with hands that foolishly sliced through the air,
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて
and I drew a single cloud on a piece of paper,
笑って握ってみせて
smiled, and showed you as I squeezed it.
忘れないように
So that I don't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it doesn't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
because what remains in history isn't everything.
今だけ顔をなくして
Losing my face just for now,
言葉を全部忘れて
forgetting all my words,
君は笑ってる
you're smiling,
夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
we're ghosts waiting for summer.
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more of your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
tell me the scent of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
I take shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So that I don't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it doesn't fade away,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
because what resonates in the heart isn't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
even tell me "goodbye,"
今も見るんだよ
I still see them,
夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
ghosts in the flowers blooming in summer.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time,
時間じゃなくて心を
not time, but the heart,
浅い呼吸をする
I take shallow breaths,
汗を拭って夏めく
wiping away sweat, becoming like summer.
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten,
夏の木陰に座ったまま
while sitting in the shade of summer,
アイスを口に放り込んで
popping ice cream into our mouths,
風を待っていた
we waited for the wind.
はい、ということで、花に亡霊でした！
All right, that was "Ghost in a Flower"!
AZKi先輩、ようこそ！
AZKi-senpai, welcome!
お邪魔します！
Thank you for having me!
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆さん、コンコンコン、コンあずき！
Everyone, kon-kon-kon, Kon-AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図。あなたのハートをゼロ決済！
Microphone in my right hand, map in my left. Reaching your heart at zero distance!
ということで、AZKiです！
This is AZKi!
ようこそです！
Welcome!
わあ、すごい素敵なライブにご招待いただきありがとうございます。
Wow, thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful live concert.
こちらこそご出演いただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for performing with me!
嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
はい、この曲はですね、あのAZKi先輩にちょっと歌いたい曲アンケートみたいな、
Yes, about this song, I sent AZKi-senpai a survey about songs we'd like to sing together,
すごい前にね、アンケートありましたね。
quite a while back.
はい、アンケートありましたね。
Yes, we had that survey.
そちらでこよりと一緒に歌いたい曲だとかに書いてくださっていた楽曲でした。
And this was a song she wrote down as something she wanted to sing with Koyori.
そう、やっぱり「夏」って聞いて、この曲は外せないなと思いまして。
Exactly. When I thought of "summer," I felt this song was a must.
そうですね！
Right!
しかもあの、アコースティックにめちゃくちゃ合う！
Plus, it fits the acoustic vibe so perfectly!
めちゃくちゃ合う！
It really does!
まあ、あのコメント欄でもあったんですけど、あの「これAZKiちのお箱やん」みたいな。
Well, there were comments saying things like, "This is AZKi-chi's signature song."
え、負けてて、でもこよちゃんも歌ってるの見かけてて。
But I've seen Koyori-chan singing it too.
よく歌う、あの。
I sing it often, actually.
せっかくだから、やっぱこの夏の終わりに歌いたいなと思って選びました。
Since we have the chance, I chose it because I wanted to sing it at the end of summer.
ねー。めちゃ浄化されました、横で歌ってて。
Right? I felt so purified singing next to you.
え、こよちゃんどうでしたか？
And what did you think, Koyori-chan?
いや、本当に良かったし、え、どうですか？
No, it was truly great. And what about you?
なんかお箱だけど、このアコースティックとかで歌ったことってございます？
Even though it's your signature song, have you ever sung it acoustically before?
あ、でもあんまりないかも。
Actually, I don't think I have that much.
おっ！
Oh!
いや、しかもね、なんかこよちゃんと一緒に歌うことで、なんかこう、
And you know, singing it together with Koyori-chan, it was like...
え、「あずこよ」ある？
Wait, is there an "AzuKoyo" moment?
え、「あずこよ」ある？「あずこよ」ある？
Oh, an "AzuKoyo" moment? "AzuKoyo" moment?
「あずこよ」あるぞっていうね、コメントをちらほら見かけました。
I saw some comments saying, "There's an AzuKoyo moment!"
見ました、見ました！嬉しいー！ありがとうございます。
I saw them too! I'm so happy! Thank you.
こよりもAZKi先輩の透き通ってる声を、お邪魔しないようにもう頑張って透き通らせて...
I tried my best to make my voice as clear as yours, AZKi-senpai, so I wouldn't get in the way...
みんな床になってくれてるみたいで
It seems everyone has become the floor.
あーよかったよかった。ありがとうございます
Aah, thank goodness. Thank you very much.
こよりちゃんなんと！
Koyori-chan, guess what!
はい！
Yes!
Xトレンド1位！
Trending #1 on X!
えー！嬉しい！
Ehh! I'm so happy!
わー！みんなありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Wow! Thank you everyone! Thank you very much!
もっともっと呟いちゃってください
Please keep tweeting more and more.
嬉しい！はい、ありがとう
I'm so happy! Yes, thank you.
それではですね、ちょっともっと語りたいこともあるんですけども
Well then, there are more things I'd like to talk about, but...
そろそろ次の曲に行きたいと思うのですが
...I think it's about time to move on to the next song.
次のメンバーをまず呼び込みたいと思いますよ！
First, I'd like to call in the next members!
ミオ先輩とビブー！
Mio-senpai and Bijou!
ミオちゃん、ビブー！しゅしゅしゅしゅしゅ！
Mio-chan, Bijou! Shushushushu!
イェーイ！お、元気元気！
Yay! Oh, they're so energetic!
元気あり余ってる！
Brimming with energy!
元気元気！
Energetic, energetic!
すごーい！なんかちょっとエモくてしっとり...
Amazing! It was a bit emotional and mellow...
ねー、しっとりしたねー
Yeah, it was mellow, wasn't it?
そうですね、二人でさ...
That's right, with the two of us...
あれあれ？袖からだったから...
Oh? Since we were backstage...
二人は元気してたんですけどね。偉い！すごい！
The two of them were being so energetic though. Good job! Amazing!
はーい、偉い！で、偉い？
Yes, good job! Wait, good job?
偉い？エモい？
Good job? Emotional?
エモい！エモい！エモい！偉い！
Emotional! Emotional! Emotional! Good job!
エモスティック？ん？エモティック？
Emostick? Hmm? Emotic?
エモーショナル！エモーショナル！
Emotional! Emotional!
エモーショナルにお届けしております
We are delivering it emotionally.
あ、ではですね、ここでちょっとあずき先輩お着替えに。
Ah, well then, AZKi-senpai is going to change now.
あ、ちょっとお着替えしてきます！
Ah, I'm going to go change for a bit!
いってらっしゃーい！お願いします
Have a good one! See you!
でもエモーショナルといえば、ロックンロールかと思っていたカリ先輩とビブーの「風といっしょに」もめちゃ良かったですよ
But speaking of emotional, Calli-senpai and Bijou's 'Kaze to Issho ni', which I thought would be rock and roll, was also really good.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
だから、あの、みんな「え、ロックじゃないの？」みたいな。戸惑ってるのも...
So, everyone was like, 'Eh, it's not rock?'. Seeing them confused was...
ロックじゃないよ、ロックじゃないよ
It's not rock, it's not rock.
あ、お帰りなさい！
Oh, welcome back!
早い！早い！お着替え早い！
Fast! Fast! You changed so fast!
はい、というわけで。夏はね、エモい曲が多い感じ位ですけど、次からはどうなるのか。
Yes, and so. Summer feels like it has many emotional songs, but how will it be from now on?
ここからはですね、3曲続けてお届けいたします！
From here, we will deliver three songs in a row!
次の曲はですね、こちらのあずき先輩、ミオ先輩、ビブーちゃんの3人に歌っていただきますので。
For the next song, these three—AZKi-senpai, Mio-senpai, and Bijou-chan—will be singing.
はーい！頑張るぞー！
Yes! Let's do our best!
こよりはしばらくバイバイです！
Koyori will say goodbye for a while!
おー、頑張ってね！頑張るよー！
Oh, good luck! We'll do our best!
ここで一発やっぱロックンロール？
Maybe some rock and roll here after all?
え、ロックンロール？！え？！
Eh, rock and roll?! What?!
ちょっと台本にないことを！戸惑ってる
Hey, that wasn't in the script! They're confused.
はい、というわけでね。まあ、ここから3曲続くんですけど、じゃあこの3人で歌わせていただきます。
Yes, and so. Well, three songs will follow from here, so the three of us will sing for you.
それでは聴いてください。スパークル。
Now, please listen. Sparkle.
スパークル [original ver.]
作詞・作曲：野田洋次郎
Sparkle [original ver.]
Lyrics & Composition: Yojiro Noda
まだこの世界は
Still this world is...
僕を飼いならしてたいみたいだ
...looking like it wants to keep me tamed.
望み通りだろう
Just as you wish, right?
美しくもがくよ
I will struggle beautifully.
互いの砂時計
Our respective hourglasses...
眺めながらキスをしようよ
...let's kiss while watching them.
「さよなら」から一番遠い
At the place furthest away...
場所で待ち合わせよう
...from "goodbye," let's meet up.
ついに時はきた
Finally, the time has come.
昨日までは序章の序章で
Until yesterday, it was just the prologue of the prologue.
飛ばし読みでいいから
You can just skim through it...
こっからが僕だよ
...because from here on, it's the real me.
経験と知識と
With experience, knowledge...
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
...and a courage that's started to get moldy...
いまだかつてないスピードで
...at a speed never seen before...
君のもとへダイブを
...I'll dive towards you.
まどろみの中で 生温いコーラに
In a slumber, in a lukewarm cola...
ここでないどこかを 夢見たよう
...it's like I dreamed of somewhere that isn't here.
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window...
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
...on mornings being carried away, swayed by the train.
ああ
Ah...
運命だとか未来だとか
Words like "fate" or "future"...
って言葉がどれだけ手を
...no matter how much...
伸ばそうと届かない
...they reach out, they won't reach...
場所で僕ら恋をする
...the place where we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
Even the hands of the clock...
横目に見ながら進む
...advance while glancing sideways at us.
こんな世界を二人で
In a world like this, the two of us...
一生いや何章でも
...for a lifetime, no, for however many chapters...
生き抜いて
...let's survive...
いこう
...and go.
初めましてなんてさ
"Nice to meet you," you say
はるか彼方へと追いやって
Shooting it off into the far distance
千年周期を
A thousand-year cycle
一日で生かしよう
Let's live it out in a single day
辞書にある言葉で
With words found in a dictionary
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world built from them
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope
八月の有る朝
One morning in August
君は僕の前で
You were in front of me
はにかんでは澄ましてみせた
Showing me a shy, composed smile
この世界の教科書
A textbook of this world
のような笑顔で
With a smile like that
嘘みたいな日々を 規格外の意味を
The dreamlike days, the extraordinary meanings
悲劇だっていいから 望んだよ
Even if it's a tragedy, I wished for it
そしたらドアの外に
And then, outside the door
君が全部抱えて立っていたよ
You were standing there, holding it all
運命だとか未来とか
Things like fate or the future
って言葉がどれだけ手を
Words like those, no matter how much
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で
I stretch my hand out, at a place unreachable
僕ら
By us
遊ぼうか
Shall we play?
愛し方さえも
Even the way to love
君の匂いがした
Smelled like you
歩き方さえも
Even the way to walk
その笑い声がした
Sounded like your laughter
いつか消えてなくなる
One day it will vanish
君のすべてを
Every part of you
この眼に焼き付けて
I'll burn it into my eyes
おくことはもう権利なんかじゃない
That's no longer just a right
義務だと思うんだ
I think it's a duty
運命だとか未来とか
Things like fate or the future
って言葉がどれだけ手を
Words like those, no matter how much
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で
I stretch my hand out, at a place unreachable
僕ら恋をする
We fall in love
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock, and the two of us
横目に見ながら進む
Proceed while glancing sideways
そんな世界を二人で
In such a world, the two of us
一生 いや、何章でも
For a lifetime, no, for however many chapters
生き抜いていこう
Let's live through it
ガーネット
Garnet
グラウンド駆けてく
Running across the playground
あなたの背中は
Your back
空に浮かんだ雲よりも自由で
Is more free than the clouds in the sky
ノートに並んだ
Lined up in the notebook
四角い文字さえ
Even the square-shaped characters
すべてを照らす光に見えた
Looked like light illuminating everything
ガーネット
Garnet
好きという気持ちが分からなくて
Not knowing what the feeling of love was,
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
this time that will never return...
その意味を私に教えてくれた
...taught me what it meant.
皆さん、お待たせしましたー！
Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting!
ちょっと生ならではという感じで、原因不明の機材トラブルが起きてしまいまして
In a way that's typical of live broadcasts, we had an equipment failure for unknown reasons,
今のところ、あの、原因も分かってないんですけども
and as of right now, we still don't know the cause...
うわぁ！
Whoa!
Wow!
Our singing so good it broke the stream!
お待たせしました、復旧したので
Sorry to keep you waiting, we're back up, so...
改めて、ガーネットから始めさせていただこうと思います。
Once again, we'll start with 'Garnet'.
皆さん、お待たせしてごめんね。
Everyone, sorry for keeping you waiting.
なんかちょっと「ビリビリ」ってなったみたいで、耳とかも。
It seems there was a bit of a crackling noise, affecting your ears as well.
えー、調子合わせながら、このアコースティックライブで耳直していただければと思います。
I hope you can soothe your ears with this acoustic live while we adjust.
はい、はい。
Yes, yes.
では、ウィングさんもありがとうございます。添えていただきありがとうございます。
Now, thank you Wing-san as well. Thank you for accompanying us.
では、行きますか。
Shall we get started?
はい。
Yes.
Okay.
オッケー。
Okay!
ガーネット
Garnet
作詞・作曲：奥華子
Lyrics/Composition: Oku Hanako
グラウンド駆けてく あなたの背中は
Your back as you run across the field
空に浮かんだ雲よりも自由で
Was more free than the clouds floating in the sky
ノートに並んだ四角い文字さえ
Even the square letters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす光に見えた
Looked like a light illuminating everything
好きという気持ちが分からなくて
I didn't understand what it meant to love
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
This time that will never return
その意味を私に教えてくれた
Taught me the meaning of it
あなたと過ごした日々を
The days I spent with you
この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll sear into my heart
思い出さなくても大丈夫なように
So that I'll be okay without having to remember
いつか他の誰かを好きになったとしても
Even if I fall in love with someone else someday
あなたはずっと特別で
You will always be special
大切で
And precious to me
またこの季節が巡ってく
And this season will come around again
初めて二人で話した放課後
That after-school when we first talked, just the two of us
誰も知らない笑顔を探していた
I was looking for a smile that no one else knew
遠くであなたのハシャいでる声に
At your frolicking voice in the distance
なぜだか胸が痛くなったの
For some reason, my heart started to ache
変わってゆくことを怖がっていたの
I was afraid of things changing
ずっと友達のままいれる気がした
I felt like we could stay friends forever
終わってくものなどないと思ったの
I thought that nothing would ever end
果てしない時の中で
Within this endless time
あなたと出会えたことが
The fact that I met you
何よりも私を強くしてくれたね
Made me stronger than anything else
夢中でかける明日にたどり着いたとしても
Even if I reach the tomorrow I'm desperately running towards
あなたはずっと特別で
You will always be special
大切で
And precious to me
またこの季節がやってくる
And this season will come again
いつまでも忘れないとあなたが言ってくれた夏
The summer when you told me you'd never forget
時が流れ今頃私は涙がこぼれてきた
Time has passed, and now I find myself shedding tears
あなたと過ごした日々を
The days I spent with you
この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll sear into my heart
思い出さなくても大丈夫なように
So that I'll be okay without having to remember
離れていても
Even if we're apart
好きになったとしても
Even if I've come to love you
あなたは　ずっと
You will always be
特別で　大切で
Special and precious
またこの季節が
This season comes around
巡ってくる
Once again
打上花火
Fireworks
あの日見わたした渚を
The beach we looked out over that day
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved in the sand
君の後ろ姿
The sight of you from behind
寄り返す波が　足元をよぎり
The returning waves wash over my feet
何かをさらう
Taking something away
夕凪の中
In the evening calm
日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
Only the sunset passes by
パッと光って咲いた　花火を見ていた
I was watching the fireworks bloom with a flash
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, the summer that hasn't ended yet...
曖昧な心を　解かして繋いだ
...melted and connected our vague hearts
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
あと何度君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can see the fireworks with you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
What can I do for that smiling face?
傷つくこと　喜ぶこと　繰り返す波と情動
Getting hurt, feeling joy, repeating waves and emotions
焦燥　最終列車の音
Impatience, the sound of the last train
何度でも　言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
No matter how many times, I'll put it into words and call your name
波を選び　もう一度
Choosing the waves, once more
もう二度と　悲しまずに　済むように
So that we never have to be sad again
ハッとお息のめば　消えちゃいそうな光が
The light that seemed like it would vanish if I caught my breath
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
Was surely still living in my heart
手を伸ばせば触れた　あったかい未来は
The warm future I could touch if I reached out
ひそかにふたりを見ていた
Was secretly watching the two of us
パッと花火が　夜に咲いた
The fireworks bloomed with a flash in the night
パッと花火が
With a flash, the fireworks...
夜に咲いて　静かに消えた
Bloomed in the night and quietly faded away
夜に咲いた
...bloomed in the night
離さないで　もう少しだけ
Don't let go, just for a little while longer
離さないで
Don't let go
もう少しだけ　このままで
Just for a little while longer, let's stay like this
もう少しだけ
Just for a little while longer
あの日見わたした渚を
The beach we looked out over that day
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words carved in the sand
君の後ろ姿
The sight of you from behind
パッと光って咲いた　花火を見ていた
I was watching the fireworks bloom with a flash
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, the summer that hasn't ended yet...
続いて欲しかった
I wanted it to continue
(歌唱：ラララ...)
(Vocalizing: La la la...)
はい、ということで、カリオペちゃんと打上花火を歌わせていただきました！
Alright, so, Calliope-chan and I performed "Uchiage Hanabi"!
花火きれいでした！
The fireworks were beautiful!
イェーイ！
Yay!
うわー、楽しかった！
Whoa, that was fun!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
わー、とっても楽しかったよ！
Whoa, it was a lot of fun!
嬉しい！ カリオペちゃんとこうやって
I'm so happy! Being able to duet with Calliope-chan
デュエットできる日が来るとは思わず、もう本当...
like this, I never thought the day would come, really...
イェーイ！
Yay!
頑張りました、低い声で。
I did my best with my low voice.
もうかっこよかった、めっちゃかっこよかった！
You were so cool, really cool!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
もうコントラストがすごい好きだから、そう低い声でやりたいなと。
I really like the contrast, so I wanted to do it with a low voice.
すごいね、男性パートを頑張って歌ってくださいました。カリオペちゃん、ありがとう！
It's amazing, she worked hard to sing the male part. Thank you, Calliope-chan!
こちらこそ、ありがとうございました！ 楽しかった。
Likewise, thank you very much! It was fun.
楽しかった！
It was fun!
ということで、ここでね、またじゃあメンバーのみんなを呼びたいと思います！
And so, I'd like to call all the members back here again!
全員集合！
Everyone, assemble!
Come on!
はい、最高だった！
Yes, it was great!
よかったね！
It was great, wasn't it!
もうずっと最高です！
It's been great the whole time!
素敵でした。ありがとうございます。
It was wonderful. Thank you very much.
ということでですね、改めまして。
And so, once again.
本日はアコースティックライブ、出演いただき、そして見ていただきありがとうございます！
Thank you all for performing in and watching today's acoustic live!
ありがとう！ Thank you so much!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
もう本当に、選曲神だったなって自分で思うぐらいね、
Honestly, everyone's singing was so wonderful that
皆さんの歌声が素晴らしくて、自画自賛です。
I even think my song selection was god-tier—self-praise, I know.
自画自賛だ(笑)
Self-praise, haha.
自画自賛するぐらい皆さんが本当に素晴らしくて、
You were all so wonderful that I feel like praising myself for it.
幸せなひとときを過ごさせていただきました。ありがとうございました！
I had a very happy time. Thank you!
とは言えですね、なんと次が最後の曲になってしまいました！
That said, unfortunately, the next song will be the last!
ええー！ 今来たばっかりー！
Nooo! I just got here!
今来たばっかりだよ。ラストはこの全員揃って歌いますので、
You just got here. For the final song, everyone will sing together,
お楽しみにして頂けると嬉しいんですが、ラストに行く前に...
so please look forward to it. But before we get to the last song...
ちょっとせっかくなんで、ピアノの前でスクショタイムとか...
Since we're all here, how about a screenshot time in front of the piano...
おおー！ 素敵！ ナイスアイディア！ 思い出、思い出！
Ooh! Wonderful! Nice idea! Memories, memories!
皆さんも撮ってください。
Everyone, please take pictures too.
はい、では戻りますか。ぜひぜひツイートしてくださいね。
Alright, shall we go back? Please be sure to tweet them.
夏の思い出になりました。
It became a summer memory.
ハッシュタグよろしくお願いします。
Please use the hashtag.
では、最後の曲に行く前に一言ずつ頂こうかなと思います。
Now, I'd like to get a few words from everyone before the last song.
ビジュー、どうだった？
Bijou, how was it?
えっと、めっちゃ楽しかった！
Um, it was so much fun!
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんなすごいでしょ？ ビジューもすごかった？
Everyone is amazing, right? Was Bijou amazing too?
すごかったよ！
You were amazing!
あへっあへっありがとう！
Ahe-ahe, thank you!
"Japanese is very good sugoi"ってコメントいっぱいありがとうございました！
Thank you for all the "Japanese is very good sugoi" comments!
あ、あ、ありがとう！ 日本語もうちょっと難しいですけど、
Th-th-thank you! Japanese is still a bit difficult, but
頑張りたいです！ そう思ってね。
I want to do my best! That's what I think.
すごかったよ、めっちゃプラクティスしてくれて。
You were amazing, you practiced so much.
めっちゃプラクティス！ 本当すごい！
So much practice! Truly amazing!
Good job, Bijou!
ENのライブ、8月にありまして。そちらのアーカイブが
There was an EN live in August. I think the archive is
9月25日とかまでだったかな。もうちょっと見れますので、ぜひそちらも見てください。
available until around September 25th. You can still watch it, so please check it out.
チェックしてね！ ありがとう！
Check it out! Thank you!
そして、カリ先輩。
And, Calli-senpai.
私、もっと歌いたかった... この夜が続いて欲しかった... みたいな。
I wanted to sing more... I wanted this night to continue... Something like that.
あと足りなそう、あと3倍ぐらいは歌いたそう。
It feels like it's not enough, I want to sing about 3 times more.
3時間いけそう。
We could go for 3 hours.
打上花火
Uchiage Hanabi
あー、うん。
Aah, yeah.
生3Dライブ、そうそうそう、やってたから。
Yeah, we've been doing live 3D concerts, so...
まあ、超お久しぶりですね。ずっとまたやりたかったけど、まあ機会がなくて。
It's been quite a long time. I've always wanted to do this again, but I didn't have the chance.
結構収録がね、あの、入るようになったりしましたからね。
Recordings have been keeping us quite busy lately.
そうだね。だから本当にありがとうございます。とても楽しかったです。
That's true. So thank you so much. I had a lot of fun.
なんか照れ照れしてる、可愛い！
She's blushing! So cute!
めっちゃかっこよかった！
You were so cool!
あとカリ先輩は今日ね、ミスの5周年のライブから駆けつけで。
And Calli-senpai rushed here right after her 5th anniversary live today.
すごーい！超ハードスケジュール！お疲れ様です！
Wow! That's a super tight schedule! Good job!
できないそんなこと。お忙しいですね。
I could never do that. You're so busy!
あれもチェックしてほしい。
I hope you check that out too.
ね。そう、是非ですね、こちらアーカイブもあるので是非。
Right. Yes, the archive is available, so please go see it.
頑張りました。Busy, busy, very busyだけど楽しいから。
I worked hard. Busy, busy, very busy, but it's fun.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you as well.
そして、ミオ先輩！
And now, Mio-senpai!
はい！いや、こうやってね、みんなとね、一緒に歌うってことが楽しかったね。
Yes! Well, it was so much fun to sing together with everyone like this.
うん。すごいね、あの今日貴重な時間を貰えて本当に嬉しかったです。今日ありがとう！
Yeah. I'm really glad I could share this precious time today. Thank you!
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます！
No, thank you so much!
いや本当ミオ先輩はソロライブ終わったばかりで、そっちも大変だったのにも関わらずね。
Really, Mio-senpai just finished her solo live, so she was busy too, and yet...
でもなんか出たいなーって思ったんだけど、なんかどうなってるか不安だから、ちょっと曲数は少なくしてもらったんだけど。
I really wanted to be here, but I was worried about how I'd hold up, so I asked to have fewer songs.
それでも1曲少ないだけになっております。
Even so, she's only doing one less song.
そうなんですよ。気遣いいただきありがとうございます。
That's right. Thank you for being so considerate.
でも出れてよかった。あとソロライブも本当最高だったし、アーカイブね、ありますんで是非皆さん見てください。
But I'm glad I came. My solo live was great too, and the archive is up, so please check it out.
チェック！イェーイ！
Check it out! Yeah!
そして、あずき先輩！
And now, AZKi-senpai!
いや本当に今日、いい時間を、最高の時間を過ごさせていただきました。見てくださった方もありがとうございましたっていうのと。
I truly had a wonderful, wonderful time today. Thank you to everyone who watched.
あと、今回こよちゃんが主催してくれてこのライブがありますので、こよちゃんありがとうと。
Also, this live happened because Koyo-chan organized it, so thank you, Koyo-chan.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you as well.
Vingさんも、あの素敵な演奏ありがとうございます。
Ving-san, thank you for the wonderful performance too.
ありがとうございます！本当最高でした。素晴らしい。
Thank you! It was truly the best. Wonderful.
いや、またin Summerですか？in Winterあるんですか？
So, 'in Summer'... will there be an 'in Winter'?
えー！やりたいなーっていう気持ちを込めて、ね。
What?! Well, with the hope that we can do it, right?
4回できますよね。声次第ですよね。今日のライブの感想とかを…
We could do it four times a year. It depends on the support! If you could tell us your thoughts on today's live...
是非是非教えていただけたらなと思います。ありがとうございます。
I hope you'll share your thoughts on today's live. Thank you so much.
お願いします。そしてあずき先輩は11月にソロライブがありますんで、よかったら是非見に来ていただけたら嬉しいです。
Please do. And AZKi-senpai has a solo live in November, so we'd be happy if you came to see it.
めちゃくちゃ楽しみ！配信チケットもありますんで是非ご覧ください。
I'm so looking forward to it! There are streaming tickets too, so please check it out.
はい。ということでですね、今日、本当にこの主催をしてみたのは、みんなの歌聴きたい、みんなと一緒に歌いたいみたいな気持ちもすごいありまして。
Right. So, I decided to host this because I really wanted to hear everyone sing and sing together with everyone.
そしてピアノと一緒に歌いたいっていう気持ちもすごいありまして、やったんですけど、本当に最高の時間でした。ありがとう！
And I also really wanted to sing with a piano. I'm so glad we did, it's been a truly wonderful time. Thank you!
ありがとう！またやろう！
Thank you! Let's do it again!
最後の曲でちょっとね、名残惜しいんですけど、はい。このまま歌わせていただきたいと思います。皆さん何の曲だと思いますか？
It's a bit sad that we're at the last song, but yes. We'd like to sing it now. Everyone, what song do you think it is?
What song do you think we're going to sing last, chat? Do we see your guesses?
What song do you think we're going to sing last, chat? Let's see your guesses.
皆さんの予想は？ラストソング何？
What are your guesses? What's the last song?
ラストソング、ラストソング…何？Guess! Guess! ラストソングをゲスできるのかな？
Last song, last song... What is it? Guess! Guess! Can they guess the last song?
SSS?
あ、SSS。確かに。
Ah, SSS. Certainly.
アセシュアーカイブ？
Ase-shu Archive?
あ、それ最初に流れてたから！歌うって思うよね。
Oh, because that was played at the beginning! People would think we'd sing that.
うんうん。正解もありそうです。すごい。
Yeah, yeah. Some people might be right. Wow.
結構割れてますだ。結構夏の歌といえば…というこの曲で締めさせていただきたいと思います。
The guesses are quite split. I'd like to close with this song, which is a classic summer song...
それでは聴いてください。secret base ～君がくれたもの～
Please listen: secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~
secret base ～君がくれたもの～
作詞・作曲：町田紀彦
secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~
Lyrics & Composition: Norihiko Machida
君と夏の終わり　将来の夢　大きな希望　忘れない
You and the end of summer, our dreams for the future, and our great hopes—I won't forget them.
10年後の8月　また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
最高の思い出を…
Those wonderful memories...
出会いはふっとした瞬間　帰り道の交差点で
Our meeting was a sudden moment at the intersection on the way home.
声をかけてくれたね　「一緒に帰ろう」
You called out to me, "Let's go home together."
僕は照れくさそうに　カバンで顔を隠しながら
Looking embarrassed, I hid my face behind my bag.
...を隠しながら
...while hiding it...
本当にとてもとても 嬉しかったよ
I was truly, very, very happy.
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとせつなく
Ah, fireworks bloomed beautifully in the night sky, making me feel a bit sentimental.
あぁ 風が時間とともに流れる
Ah, the wind flows along with time.
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険もいろいろしたね
We were happy and having fun, and went on all sorts of adventures.
二人の秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
The end of summer with you, our dreams for the future, and our big hopes—I won't forget them.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」 叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら 切ないよね
Holding back tears and saying goodbye with a smile is so painful.
最高の思い出を
The best of memories...
あぁ 夏休みもあと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, because summer vacation will be over in just a little while.
あぁ 太陽と月仲良くして
Ah, I wish the sun and the moon would get along.
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩もいろいろしたね
We were sad and lonely, and had all sorts of fights.
二人の秘密の基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」 叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら 切ないよね
Holding back tears and saying goodbye with a smile is so painful.
最高の思い出を
The best of memories...
突然の
Suddenly...
転校で
...with the school transfer...
どうしようもなく
...there was nothing I could do.
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ 忘れないでね 僕のことを
I'll write letters, I'll call you, so please don't forget me.
いつまでも二人の基地の中
Always inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して 夕日を見てから星を眺め
At the end of summer with you, we talked forever, watching the sunset and then the stars.
君の頬を流れた涙はずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears that flowed down your cheeks.
君が最後まで大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll surely never forget how you waved your hand so hard until the very end.
だからこうして夢の中でずっと永遠に
So, just like this, forever in my dreams...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
The end of summer with you, our dreams for the future, and our big hopes—I won't forget them.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing that we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」 叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were shouting "Thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら 切ないよね
Holding back tears and saying goodbye with a smile is so painful.
最高の思い出を
The best of memories...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Thanks everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
Thank you!
またねー！
See you soon!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Peace!
Thank you guys so much for coming tonight!
Thank you so much for watching, everyone!
本日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for today!
最高の夏休みになりましたー！
This has been the best summer vacation!
みんな、また会おうねー！
Everyone, let's meet again soon!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!